VINEET DUBEY | SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Software engineer with 4+ years of experience as a back-end developer working on enterprise applications, distributed microservices and IoT platforms in Java and Scala. Expertise in building APIs and server software using Play/Akka and Spring Boot as well as writing unit tests and debugging. Working knowledge of MongoDB, InfluxDB and general RDBMS. Ability to collaborate efficiently in a team.

CONTACT



Phone

+91 9833 023 159



Email

vineetvdubey@hotmail.com



LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/vineetvdubey

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering

Electronics and Telecommunications University of Mumbai 2012 - 2016

CERTIFICATES

- Oracle Certified Professional, JAVA SE6 Programmer
- Oracle SQL Fundamentals I

KEY SKILLS

• JAVA 8

• SPRING BOOT

• KAFKA

• SCALA

• PLAY FRAMEWORK

• JUNIT

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | Kuliza Technologies, Bengaluru

November 2019 - Present

Roles:

- Designed and built an automation framework dedicated to test data flowing through Kafka Queues
- Involved in saas provider integration to crawl files for CASB (Cloud Access Security Broker)
- Implemented a micro-service to collect statistics on client data
- Actively involved in peer reviews, design brainstorming sessions and mentoring juniors

Technologies:

- Java 8, Spring Boot, Microservices
- Kafka, Zookeeper, H2DB, Automation Scripting

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | *Enlite Research, Mumbai*

May 2018 - September 2019

Roles:

- Built REST APIs in Scala, Java + Play for client dashboard
- Improved and expanded the core logic for Enlite's IoT Platform
- Coordinated with the hardware team and set up 'Design Contracts' to ensure smooth communication between the IoT sensors and the platform
- Worked with UI/UX Team to develop/improve APIs for the dashboard
- Maintained internal systems deployed on AWS including the in-house VPN server, Wiki, Bug reporting system etc.

Technologies:

- Scala, Java, Akka, Play Framework
- MongoDB, InfluxDB, AngularJS, Git

ASSOCIATE SYSTEMS ENGINEER | TCS, Chennai

August 2016 - March 2018

Roles:

- Worked as web application developer for a US based client
- Operated closely with other team members to plan, design and develop robust solutions based on customer's business requirement
- Developed unit tested and maintainable code by following industry level code quality standards
- Created technical documents/manuals

Technologies:

- Core Java, JavaEE, Servlet, JSP, JQuery, Struts, Spring MVC
- Unit Testing frameworks JUnit, Mockito, PIT Mutation
- Apache Subversion, Maven, SQL